MR BLESSON THOMAS **MENG MIET**

Date of birth: 31/07/1987

Web: https://uk.linkedin.com/in/blessonthomasmeng

Nationality:

Apartment 29, 2 Advent Way, Manchester M4 7LH,

Address: **United Kingdom** Phone number: 07806632933

Email address: blesson.thomasraju@gmail.com



PROFILE

Professional minded person with a proven leadership in managing and delivering major infrastructure portfolio of projects.

Proven experience in project lifecycle management and collaborating with key stakeholders and clients to deliver projects within costs, time and quality.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Project Engineer 09/2017 - present WSP, Manchester, United Kingdom

Managing and supporting the project management team for the successful delivery of multi-discipline Interconnector projects.

Support the project team to ensure that the appropriate resources are utilised on projects to the satisfaction of the client and business needs.

Preparing and ensuring that projects are delivered in line with programme, quality and margins.

Financial reporting responsibilities including financial status reports, project reviews and risk register. Achieved time, cost and performance objectives by identifying possible deviations from the project baseline, and proposing preventative and corrective

actions.

Actively developing external and internal client relationships.

Preparing key technical and commercial documents to update the client and the external customers on the progress of the project.

Supporting the client by getting involved in planning consultations and supplier engagement to produce the desired outputs for the project.

Collaborate and develop the key relationship with external and internal stakeholders.

Develop and produce strategies for procurement, maintenance and repair and contract awarding activities.

Assist in the definition of project scope and objectives, involving all relevant stakeholders and ensuring technical feasibility.

Change management plans development.

Confirm all project documentation is complete and in compliance with each phase.

Investment Delivery Engineer 04/2016 - 08/2017 National Grid, Warwick, United Kingdom

Overview

Responsible for leading the project team and developing the business case for National Grid's new transmission infrastructure to connect key portfolio of generation projects (£100K to £100M+). Project Lead in projects with high degree of technical

🗎 WORK EXPERIENCE

risk and been delivered within budget, time and meeting customer expectations.

Ensuring that all projects are developed and delivered in the most economic and safe manner. Project leading, preparation, planning, execution and finalization of project.

Ensuring that the business case accurately justifies National Grid's investment long term strategy decisions.

Achieved time, cost and performance objectives by identifying possible deviations from the project baseline, and proposing preventative and corrective actions.

Key outputs:

Leading in the development and delivery of Project Briefs for the portfolio of schemes, developing solutions and preparing a project execution plan to ensure that these objectives are delivered in line with the transmission strategy.

Managing and leading the optioneering with key stakeholders to find feasible solutions for the business case and ensuring that they fit within the regulatory and funding requirements of the business case.

Accountable for managing the strong relationship with key stakeholders across each project and ensuring that funding is in place during the development and construction activities for the preferred solution.

Working closely with the steering group and governance parties to support the regulatory submissions and strategic project decision-making. Actively monitoring the progress of all schemes to ensure that they are delivered under the

requirements of needs case and sanctioned costs. This also involves leading the scheme to agree and challenge investments which are out of scope and agree re-sanctions with the executive board.

Leading and engaging with the customers across the portfolio of projects through the development and delivery of projects.

Contributed to design and construction ideas to the project teams.

Develop a detailed project plan to monitor and track progress.

Gathering of individual project and producing performance reporting for management review. Challenging the project team on the relevant projects to deliver innovative and fit for purpose options adding value through the project lifecycle. Accountable in key decision making of projects from concept to delivery to ensure the objectives are met.

Accountable for change control to ensure that any deviation are managed in accordance with change control framework.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Acting as the escalation point for issues and risk through the project lifecycle and managing those risks within the project team and have mitigation in place.

Managing gate reviews for each project. preparation of handover documents to operation and reviewing the project documents during closure for each project.

Senior Power System Engineer/ Performance

Excellence Lead 09/2014 - 03/2016

National Grid, Warwick, United Kingdom

Primarily engaged with multiple clients to ensure that they deliver compliant scope to deliver the requirements for projects.

Accountable for managing the transmission projects for Scotland and East of England to ensure that they meet the right objectives.

Leading the team to deliver transmission system projects in required timescales and ensuring that they meet regulatory requirements.

Liaising with multiple stakeholders and customers to provide expertise on data assurance and quality of the transmission models.

Leading as Data Manager to ensure the transmission models are accurate and accountable for delivery of all projects to key stakeholders and clients.

Accountable for leading the team to develop and delivery of programme for the Electricity Ten Year Statement (ETYS).

Develop and prepare technical documentation and standard operating procedures for the requirements of the team objectives.

Acted as Performance Excellence Lead to collaborate with practitioners to engage, diagnosis and deliver performance optimisation in processes.

Power System Engineer 08/2012 – 10/2013 National Grid, Reading, United Kingdom

Accountable to deliver a compliant distribution solution by analysing and understanding requirements from major distribution networks. Responsible for managing the distribution network projects to ensure that they are compliant with the standard framework.

Working closely with the key stakeholders and ensure that the right requirements are in place to delivered in time and scope

Co-Leading the working groups with clients and stakeholders to prepare agreements for commercial operation.

EDUCATION

Electrical and Electronic

Engineering 09/2009 – 06/2014 The University of Manchester, Manchester, United Kingdom

MEng with 2:1, Electrical and Electronic Engineering at the University of Manchester

Power Systems Smart Grid Renewable Energy Power Generation Energy Policy and Regulation Electricity

Project Management Stakeholder Management Customer Management Leadership

Agile Lean Six Sigma







06/2016

CERTIFICATIONS

Construction - Construction Design and Management Regulations 2015 National Grid

Project Management 07/2016

Stakeholder and Customer Awareness National Grid (In-House)

National Grid (In-House)

08/2015

(Ongoing) Project Management Association of Project Management

GRAPHS







Microsoft Office Suite

Microsoft Project

Leadership







Customer and Stakeholder Focus Innovative

Project Manager

HOBBIES





